Fu-Chang Sun



Summary

Aspiring Data Scientist who converts data into insights supported by statistical evidence using machine learning techniques. Qualifications include 5+ years research experience, data analysis and visualization, coding proficiency, mathematical background, proven interpersonal skills, and ability of collaboration.

Education

Nanodegree Graduate in Machine Learning
Udacity, www.udacity.com

Doctor of Philosophy in Physics
University of Connecticut (UCONN), Storrs, CT

Master of Science in Physics
University at Buffalo (UB), Amherst, NY

Bachelor of Science in Math and Physics (Double Major)
National Cheng Kung University (NCKU), Tainan, Taiwan

Technical Skills

• Shell Scripting, Python, pandas, Scikit-Learn, Machine Learning, Data Visualization, Statistical Modeling, SQL, C/C++, MATLAB, Unix, LATEX

Project Experience

Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree Program at Udacity

October 2017

- Applied statistical analysis tools to predict housing prices and evaluate the predictive model by grid search technique to optimize a learning algorithm
- Utilized supervised learning models such as Decision Trees, SVMs, Neural Networks to target potential financial contributor using relational database
- Identified patterns and structures in unlabeled data of wholesale distributor's service using unsupervised learning technique and unveil its clustering for new prediction
- Implemented reinforcement learning algorithm and convolutional neural networks for image classification

Materials Hackathon (MatHack) at MRS Fall Meeting & Exhibit

December 2015

- Received the *Third Place of Materials Hackathon* by automatically collecting materials crystallographic data from wiki and AMCSD databases
- Awarded as *Special Prize for Materials Data Challenge* by sustainable and extensible research project embedding in the commercialized server

Work Experience

Research Specialist

September 2017 – Present

Department of Materials Science & Engineering, UCONN

- Perform exploratory data analysis to gain a deeper understanding with data visualization tools
- Design, develop, and test the machine learning models for creating the sustainable workflows

Research Assistant

September 2013 – January 2017

Department of Materials Science & Engineering, UCONN

- Conducted and published 7 scientific research on ferroelectric materials using computational modeling in quantum, classical, and continuum time and length scale
- Designed the theoretical-based model and analyzed the simulation results of ferroelectric devices with different stacking geometry to explain experiment observation

Lab Instructor, Teaching Assistant

September 2010 – May 2013

Department of Physics, UCONN

- Motivated student engagement by creating in-class activities and prompting discussions
- Encouraged 240+ students to develop critical thinking skills with various experiment setup